Omoefe Joseph Ugboma

Lagos, Nigeria | https://github.com/Omoefe-Ugboma/ | +2348026426407 | jkomoefey23e@yahoo.co.uk

Personal portfolio website: https://omoefe-

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/omoefe-

ugboma.netlify.app/

joseph-ugboma-3236a625/

SUMMARY

Dedicated software engineer with More than five years of experience in web and application development, and as well as a software specialist. And also, a JavaScript developer with strong hands-on in ReactJS and React-Native. Strong creative and analytical skills. Team player with an eye for detail. Strong collaborative skills and proven history of application development.

TECH STACK SKILLS

FRONT-END SKILLS	BACK-END SKILLS	FRAMEWORKS	DATABASE / Methodologies
HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Flexbox, Grid-Layout, Bootstrap, Source-Control (Git), REST APIs, CI/CD	PHP, Python, NodeJS, Java, Agile Scrum, MOB, Docker	Angular, RXJS, NGRX, Java Spring Boot, Django, ExpressJS, Vue3, VUEX, Laravel	SQL (PostgreSQL, MySQL, MS SQL Server),

EXPERIENCE

Cousant Consult / InvestmentOne Financial Service Limited | Front-End Developer (Angular)

2022 - Till date

- > Develop new user-facing features related to the current project, writing clean, sustainable, easy to read code.
- ldentifying issues with front end code and rectifying them to remove future bugs. And, also auditing codes to identify bottlenecks of performance and fixing them.
- > Communicating thoroughly with the back-end department to help build a best-practice RESTful API.
- > Building a reusable code, components and libraries for future use. And also, collaborating with other team members and stakeholders, to make it possible in other to quickly jump between projects and responsibilities.

PromateLink Solutions Limited | Full-Stack Developer

2019 - 2021

- > Designing, architecting and writing the front-end of our eCommerce application using ReactJS with a lot of reusable components.
- Collaborating with a 4-person engineering team in solving compatibility problems, and also eliminating technical issues and update development process records.
- > Built extensive test coverage for all new features, reducing the number of customer complaints by 10%.

Meta Data Technologies Limited | Full-Stack Web Application Developer [Remote]

May 2019 - Nov 2019

- Developed new React components for the customer facing web application, improving the average user time on page by 2 minutes.
- > Built the next version of client web application to add new user designs and features using ReactJS, Spring-Boot, Spring-Security and reducing reported bug issues by over 15%.

- Writing back-end API endpoints for the front-end developer to consume.
- Also creating and structuring the database tables for the endpoint to use.
- Worked to support an existing software to guide users on how to use it and also document bug reporting on it.

Forte Soft Systems Limited [NIIT EDUCATION] | Senior Faculty Head

April 2015 - May 2018

- Provided robust, comprehensive lesson plans for two different classes simultaneously while providing regular, additional support to students when requested.
- > Taught over 100 students concurrently while providing a high degree of education customization when required.

EDUCATION

National Institute of Information Technology | Honors Software Engineering (Java Technology)

Middlesex University | Information Technology and Business Information Systems

New Horizons | Diploma Software Engineering Practice

THE AGILE ADVISOR NIGERIA | Certificate of Completion Agile Scrum Mastering

2011 | Lagos.

2015 | Lagos.

PROJECTS

Jacob Esuene Squash Club Web App

ESC BLOG WEB APP

- (Designed and coded the website (using HTML5, Bootstrap 4, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, Laravel and MySQL) where players of popular squash games lovers come to play weekly and monthly competitions).
- Responded to user feedback and issues to improve site functionality and build additional features including automatic menus fully customizable at the back-end (Admin Panel).
- Full-Stack Responsive Blog Designed and coded the blog website (using HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap 4, PHP, Laravel, and JavaScript, and more) where the site admin post new updates about the clubs and recent events.

Link: https://jesconline.com | May 2020 - July 2020

Link: https://jesconline.com/blog | July 2020 - August 2020

Latest Projects: | https://github.com/Omoefe-Ugboma/